♪I lament on the cruel and untimely love♪
أنا أتحسر على الحب القاسي والغير أوانه ♪
♪Yet I come to realise it's a daydream when the bubbles burst♪
♪ ومع ذلك أدركت أنه حلم يقظة عندما تنفجر الفقاعات ♪
♪A city of spring flowers♪
♪ مدينة زهور الربيع ♪
♪Sinks into the indifferent autumnal frost♪
♪ يغرق في الصقيع الخريفي غير المبال
♪A snowflake falls into the river♪
♪ تسقط ندفة ثلجية في النهر ♪
♪The biting cold stalks over♪
♪ البرد القارص ينبع
♪All assumptions are nothing♪
كل الافتراضات لا شيء
♪But a disguised makeup♪
♪ لكن مكياج مقنع
♪I bid farewell♪
أودع
♪To the passionate gaze behind the mask♪
♪ للنظرة العاطفية خلف القناع ♪
♪Love and hate are the most unforgettable feelings♪
الحب والكراهية من أكثر المشاعر التي لا تنسى
♪Overwhelmed by my longings♪
غارقة في شوقي ♪
♪I tear off those old scores♪
♪ مزقت تلك الدرجات القديمة ♪
♪I bid farewell♪
أودع
♪To the irretrievable past♪
إلى الماضي الذي لا يمكن استرجاعه ♪
=Little Mad Doctor=
= الطبيب المجنون الصغير =
=Episode 23=
= الحلقة 23 =
Ling'er.
لينغ.
Where's my wedding gown?
أين ثوب زفافي؟
What?
ماذا؟
The wedding gown you brought back.
ثوب الزفاف الذي أعدته.
Wait, Your Highness.
انتظر يا صاحب السمو.
It's here.
إنه هنا.
♪At the end of the bustling world, I met you♪
♪ في نهاية العالم الصاخب ، التقيت بك ♪
How smart of you, Ling'er.
كم هو ذكي منك يا لينجير.
♪Two people from two different worlds♪
♪ شخصان من عالمين مختلفين
Luckily I'm smart enough
لحسن الحظ أنا ذكي بما فيه الكفاية
to not burn the gown.
حتى لا تحرق الثوب.
♪Crispy melody of the flute from outside the city♪
لحن الناي المقرمش من خارج المدينة ♪
♪Full of nostalgia♪
♪ مليئة بالحنين ♪
♪Despite love being dreamlike♪
♪ على الرغم من حبك لكونك كالحلم ♪
♪All I'm waiting for is you♪
♪ كل ما أنتظره هو أنت ♪
♪Myriad of illnesses in this world♪
♪ عدد لا يحصى من الأمراض في هذا العالم
Look at this.
انظر إلى هذا.
♪Flower petals rain down the lake♪
♪ بتلات الزهور تمطر أسفل البحيرة ♪
This is beautiful.
هذا جميل.
That's right.
صحيح.
♪Who can't leap over the gate of love♪
من لا يستطيع القفز فوق بوابة الحب
♪Myriad of illnesses in this world♪
♪ عدد لا يحصى من الأمراض في هذا العالم
♪Only lovesick is incurable♪
فقط مريض الحب لا علاج له ♪
Longsan.
لونجسان.
Where's His Highness?
أين سموه؟
His Highness already went out.
سموه خرج بالفعل.
He went out?
لقد خرج؟
Why didn't you follow him
لماذا لم تتبعه
and protect him?
وتحميه؟
His Highness stopped us from following.
سموه منعنا من المتابعة.
Besides,
بجانب،
if there were troubles,
إذا كانت هناك مشاكل ،
we would slow him down.
سنبطئه.
Huh?
هاه؟
♪Who can't leap over the gate of love♪
من لا يستطيع القفز فوق بوابة الحب
♪Myriad of illnesses in this world♪
عدد لا يحصى من الأمراض في هذا العالم
Yu Longyuan.
يو لونجيوان.
♪My deep affection is beyond cure♪
♪ عاطفتي العميقة لا يمكن علاجها ♪
♪The message from the wind♪
الرسالة من الريح ♪
♪Transcends life cycle and reaches us♪
يتجاوز دورة الحياة ويصل إلينا
♪Can we find♪
♪ هل يمكن أن نجد ♪
♪Proof of our love?♪
دليل على حبنا؟
I, Chu Jinghong,
أنا ، تشو جينغهونغ ،
never believe in natural powers and deities.
لا تؤمن أبدًا بالقوى والآلهة الطبيعية.
But today, I believe them.
لكني أصدقهم اليوم.
Jinghong.
جينغهونغ.
My Lord.
ربي.
Say no more.
قل لا زيادة.
Here and now,
هنا و الآن،
with the heavens as our witness,
مع السماوات كشاهدتنا ،
the earth as our matchmaker
الأرض مثل الخاطبة لدينا
and the deities as our guarantors,
والآلهة ضامنين لنا ،
do you consent
هل توافق
to take me as your wife?
لتأخذني كزوجة لك؟
Yes, I will.
نعم سأفعل.
I never expected to hear that
لم أتوقع أن أسمع ذلك
from the groom.
من العريس.
I, Yu Longyuan,
أنا ، يو لونجيوان ،
with the heavens as our witness,
مع السماوات كشاهدتنا ،
the earth as our matchmaker
الأرض مثل الخاطبة لدينا
and the deities as our guarantors,
والآلهة ضامنين لنا ،
take Chu Jinghong to be my wife.
خذ Chu Jinghong لتكون زوجتي.
With unwavering trust,
بثقة لا تتزعزع ،
I promise to love and cherish you
أعدك أن أحبك وأعتز به
always and forever,
دائما و ابدا،
until death do us part.
حتى يفرقنا الموت.
Our lifelong vows
عهودنا مدى الحياة
will extend into eternity.
سوف تمتد إلى الأبدية.
♪Desolate chills blow away several autumns♪
♪ قشعريرة مقفرة تهب عدة خريفات ♪
♪Eternal love is all I seek♪
الحب الأبدي هو كل ما أسعى إليه
♪Though the sweet dream fades at last♪
رغم أن الحلم الجميل يتلاشى أخيرًا ♪
♪I sigh at my life♪
♪ أنا أتنهد في حياتي ♪
♪There's nowhere to anchor on shore♪
♪ لا يوجد مكان للرسو على الشاطئ
♪Nothing to cherish in the world♪
لا شيء نعتز به في العالم
♪Except for you♪
ما عداك ♪
♪The past we've been through retains♪
♪ الماضي الذي مررنا به
♪Even though time wears thin♪
على الرغم من أن الوقت يضعف ♪
♪The thought of being together lifelong♪
فكرة البقاء معًا مدى الحياة
♪Exists beyond time♪
موجود خارج الزمن ♪
♪All joys and sorrows♪
♪ كل افراح و احزان ♪
♪Reflect in your gentle gaze♪
انعكس في نظراتك اللطيفة
♪I will spend my life waiting♪
♪ سأقضي حياتي في الانتظار ♪
♪For the chance to be forever by your side♪
للحصول على فرصة أن تكون بجانبك إلى الأبد
Jinghong.
جينغهونغ.
Wait for me.
الانتظار لي.
My Lord.
ربي.
Time to depart.
حان وقت المغادرة.
Please protect Jinghong on my behalf.
الرجاء حماية جينغهونغ نيابة عني.
No worries.
لا شكر على واجب.
I will keep Princess Jinghong in perfect check
سأبقي الأميرة جينغهونغ في حالة فحص تام
as well as the Internal Activities Depot.
وكذلك مستودع الأنشطة الداخلية.
I will take off my mask
سوف أخلع قناعي
only on the day you return.
فقط في يوم عودتك.
Thanks.
شكرًا.
(My Lord.)
(ربي.)
(I will wait for you.)
(أنا سوف أنتظرك.)
(Juntian Gate)
(بوابة جونتيان)
My Lord.
ربي.
Are you coming back
هل سوف تعود
when the next full moon occurs?
عندما يحدث اكتمال القمر القادم؟
You scared me.
لقد أخفتني.
I went through so much trouble
لقد مررت بالكثير من المتاعب
to obtain this.
للحصول على هذا.
How are you going to thank me?
كيف ستشكرني؟
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
That's all?
هذا كل شئ؟
Yes.
نعم.
Nongying.
نونجينج.
Eastern Xia has launched an attack on Northern Chu.
شنت شيا الشرقية هجومًا على شمال تشو.
What are you going to do?
ما كنت تنوي القيام به؟
After I finish the last thing,
بعد أن أنهي آخر شيء ،
I will return to Northern Chu.
سأعود إلى شمال تشو.
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
tomorrow,
غداً،
you go and solicit an audience with the emperor.
تذهب وتطلب جمهورًا مع الإمبراطور.
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
Princess Jinghong of Northern Chu seeks an audience.
الأميرة جينغهونغ من شمال تشو تبحث عن جمهور.
Yes.
نعم.
♪I sigh at my life♪
♪ أنا أتنهد في حياتي ♪
♪There's nowhere to anchor on shore♪
♪ لا يوجد مكان للرسو على الشاطئ
♪Nothing to cherish in the world♪
لا شيء نعتز به في العالم
♪Except for you♪
ما عداك ♪
♪The past we've been through retains♪
♪ الماضي الذي مررنا به
♪Even though time wears thin♪
على الرغم من أن الوقت يضعف ♪
♪The thought of being together lifelong♪
فكرة البقاء معًا مدى الحياة
♪Exists beyond time♪
موجود خارج الزمن ♪
♪All joys and sorrows♪
♪ كل افراح و احزان ♪
♪Reflect in your gentle gaze♪
انعكس في نظراتك اللطيفة
♪I will spend my life waiting♪
♪ سأقضي حياتي في الانتظار ♪
♪For the chance to be forever by your side♪
للحصول على فرصة أن تكون بجانبك إلى الأبد
♪Hair turns grey in one winter night♪
♪ يتحول لون الشعر إلى اللون الرمادي في ليلة شتاء ♪
♪The appearance remains in spite of the thick frost♪
المظهر يبقى بالرغم من الصقيع الكثيف
♪Time slips by in that dream-like world♪
♪ الوقت يمر في هذا العالم الذي يشبه الحلم
♪Life is always full of splendor♪
♪ الحياة دائما مليئة بالروعة
♪We part when the flowers fall♪
♪ نفترق عندما تسقط الأزهار
♪Desolate chills blow away several autumns♪
♪ قشعريرة مقفرة تهب عدة خريفات ♪
♪Eternal love is all I seek♪
الحب الأبدي هو كل ما أسعى إليه
♪Though the sweet dream fades at last♪
رغم أن الحلم الجميل يتلاشى أخيرًا ♪
♪I sigh at my life♪
♪ أنا أتنهد في حياتي ♪
♪There's nowhere to anchor on shore♪
♪ لا يوجد مكان للرسو على الشاطئ
♪Nothing to cherish in the world♪
لا شيء نعتز به في العالم
♪Except for you♪
ما عداك ♪
♪The past we've been through retains♪
♪ الماضي الذي مررنا به
♪Even though time wears thin♪
على الرغم من أن الوقت يضعف ♪
♪The thought of being together lifelong♪
فكرة البقاء معًا مدى الحياة
♪Exists beyond time♪
موجود خارج الزمن ♪
♪All joys and sorrows♪
♪ كل افراح و احزان ♪
♪Reflect in your gentle gaze♪
انعكس في نظراتك اللطيفة
♪I will spend my life waiting♪
♪ سأقضي حياتي في الانتظار ♪
♪For the chance to be forever by your side♪
للحصول على فرصة أن تكون بجانبك إلى الأبد